# Gidi Morris

cv@gidi.io London, UK blog @ gidi.io
github.com/ gmmorris
in uk.linkedin.com/in/ gidimorris

# **Profile**

During my almost 20-year career in software development and team leadership, I have worked in a diverse and comprehensive array of technical and managerial roles spanning frontend, backend and infrastructure.

These roles have afforded me opportunities to lead at various levels and a variety of environments, from providing guidance and cohesive technical vision in large-scale, fast-pace start-ups, to ensuring consistent, sustainable, high-quality output within large enterprise companies.

I am driven by a deep interest in agile practices, team dynamics, continuous improvement and mentorship which I hold as equally important to technical ability, in pursuit of successful product delivery.

Alongside sustainably delivering high-quality work, I passionately believe in positively impacting my community in aspects ranging from technical achievement to diversity and inclusivity.

## Programming Skills

- Node.js, Javascript (ES5 ES9)
- ♣ Java 8+
- ReasonML & Bucklescript
- CSS, SASS & their ilk
- THE HTML, The DOM & Web APIs
- Rxis, React, Preact & their ilk
- Compile-time tooling for JS runtimes
- Functional programming, Reactive system design
- AWS, Terraform & Immutable Infrastructure
- TDD, Automated Testing (browser based & black-box)

### Methodologies & Catalytic Skills

- Individuals and Interactions over Processes and Tools
- **E**xtreme Programming, Scrum
- Pair & Mob Programming
- Mentorship & Collaboration

## DevOps Practices

- CICD, Travis, Jenkins
- Monitoring, Alerting & Structured Logging

## Work Experience

#### -

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 2019 - PRESENT

Full stack engineering of Elastic's Alerting framework within the Kibana Platform.

Owner of Kibana's TaskManager, focused on performance improvements and scaling up the infrastructure to better handle the growth in adoption of our new Alerting framework.

#### Unruly

Elastic

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | 2016 - 2019

Full stack development of the Unruly Ad Platform using *Javascript & Java* on top of *AWS-based immutable infrastructure*. Among other things this includes R&D of: Our Ad Exchange, *a multi-region distributed system* servicing thousands of requests a second. Our Supply Side Platform, a *Web Application* in *React & Redux*. A variety of Video Ad Formats and *client side solutions* in vanilla *Javascript*.

Leadership and mentorship of a 10 person development team and stewardship of the Product Development *Diversity & Inclusivity* group.

Owner of the Programmatic Demand strand, ensuring valuable prioritisation, research and implementation of deliverables in a lean, yet sustainable, manner.

Working in an XP environment ( agile, Pair & Mob Programming, Collective Ownership, & Merciless Refactoring), I have focused on collaboration, self organisation and mentorship across all aspects of product delivery and a variety of catalytic skills.

Unruly's first Nomad, providing roaming technical leadership across all development teams.

## Loveholidays

LEAD FRONT-END ARCHITECT 2014 - 2015

Managed a team of *Javascript* & *Python* developers working on the Loveholidays Web Application.

Led the top down rewrite of the entire website ( *turning spaghetti into lasagne*), converting a code base of legacy JS into a modular architecture based on *Backbone.js* and ES6. Incrementally rearchitected different parts of the site while still providing a stable code base for continued functional development.

Prototyped features using React and extensive AB Testing.

#### **Pluralis**

### SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER | 2011-2012

As the first employee at an early stage startup (pre round A) I was solely responsible for the design and implemention of the Front End architecture of our A/B testing product.

Using *Backbone.js*, *Underscore*, *jQuery*, *Bootstrap*, *LESS* and vanilla *Javascript*, I created a system for Multivariate A/B testing, an SDK for third-party developers and a web application for the management and execusion of A/B testing competitions.

I built several Javascript libraries, including a library for cross-build module management and a reverse CSS-selector engine for persistable DOM querying.

I supported development of a backend system using *Java Spring* and *AWS*. Implemented storage solutions using *MongoDB* and *CouchDB*.

#### Military

ASP.NET LEAD & DEVELOPER | 2003 - 2009

Project Management, System Analysis and Oversight of a multimillion dollar *Microsoft.Net* application.

Hands-on development, management and technical leadership of two development teams (8 people in total) working on two N-Tier *ASP.Net Web Applications*.

Technical design and development of Web Applications and Services in *Javascript* and *C#*.

Designed the data layer and integration with both the *Oracle 9i* and *SQLServer* databases.

Created and took ownership of a department wide position responsible for all UX and design work.

#### Freelance

R&D AND CONSULTING 2013

I designed and implemented *Front End* solutions consisting of application development using *Backbone.js*, workflow, build and test automation using *Grunt.js* and Back End layers and APIs using *PHP Flight* and *Node.js Express*.

Built a responsive marketing website for a mobile product including animated UX demonstrations using *Bootstrap* and both *JS animations* and *CSS3 transitions*.

Implemented data storage and caching solutions using *Redis* and *MongoDB* running on top of *AWS*.

During this time I provided services for several different companies, including ReallyGood, Conduit, Klarna and Cyhawk Ventures.

## Metacafe

WEB ENGINEER 2010-2011

Development of a Web Application using *PHP* and *Javascript* for the Metacafe portal and the site's semantic data layer in a high scale and high traffic web environment.

Designed, implemented and extended infrastructure packages using *PHP* for *Mediawiki, Semantic MediaWiki* and an in-house MVC web framework.

Integrated the Metacafe Semantic data layer with the *Sesame RDF* database.

Implemented caching layers using *Memcached* and *Varnish*, and tuned caching and eviction strategies in *PHP* and *VCL* in a massive scale environment (measuring several millions of request per day).

Implemented asynchronous workers using *Gearman* in *PHP* to perform offline processessing and semantic analysis of video content.

#### Freelance

WEB DESIGNER | 2002 - 2003

Freelance graphic designer, servicing both private clients and companies such as HP's Indigo division.

## Open Source Projects on Github.com/gmmorris

>\_ Jeff Goldblum (jg)

: A command-line JSON processor in Rust which searches for structures in JSON input and prints each matching object.

⟨/> bs-rewire : Bucklescript bindings for Rewire

⟨/⟩ Meze: A Component Composition library for Declaratively Composable Operations

⟨⟩ Safeobj : Proxy based safe property access
Simmer : Reverse CSS Selector Engine

In addition to releasing my own projects I have contributed over the years to several community Open Source projects such as *Babel, highlights.js, mootools*.

### Education

## Officer Candidate School

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGEMENT | 2006

Professional diploma

Military Officer's Training, Project and Software Development Management.

#### Mamram

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT 2003

Professional diploma

Intensive 6 month course covering development and software design principles, actual work experience in a variety of development environments such as C, C++, ASP & Javascript, Java, Perl, SQL and PL-SQL and working environments such as Windows and Unix.

COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR | 2002

High School Diploma

## Who Am I Really?

I grew up in Israel and spent the first decade of my adult life working as a software engineer for the IDF and several tech companies.

I am also an accomplished photographer, having exhibited in Israel and London, completed commercial jobs for clients in the Israeli entertainment industry and taken part in major art fairs.

I am a martial arts parctitioner and instructor, currently holding a *2nd Master* grade at Wing Tsun Kung Fu.

I am also an avid commentator on all things political and theological and was named one of Quora's Top Writers for 2014

I live in order to create, which is, I believe, why I have found such warm homes in both the startup scene and the art scene.